









ABOUT ME

MY NAME IS ALEX COVEN

I'm a 26 year old graphic designer and web developer living in Chicago. I pride myself on my eagerness and ability to learn. My longing desire to design stems from my affinity for order and geometry. Over the last few years, I have allowed myself to delve into a design and art centric lifestyle. Due to my attention to detail, I am constantly absorbing ideas from everyday life. I am very passionate about my work and driven to satisfy my clients.

EDUCATION

ALEX COVEN

DESIGNER/DEVELOPER

COLUMBIA COLLEGE CHICAGO

Graphic design major and digital media, with a web focus. Completed courses in web, type, illustration & music production. Crafted workshops for the Columbia AIGA student organization Students In Design 2009 - 2014

MAYFIELD, OH EXCEL T.E.C.C

Interactive Media, 2 year career technical program designed for digital arts, graphic design, sound design, video editing, and web development. 2007 - 2009

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE WEB & DESIGN

Experience working for a variety of clients, time management, project management, client relations, outsourcing and visual problem solving. During my time freelancing, I have had time to develop skills in design, aesthetics and the ability to operate with professionalism.

2007 - PRESENT

UBER

Senior designer, Worked on various promotional materials using my illustration and type skillsets. Worked with a PM on daily organization, was entirely responsible for design in the central region, from Canada to Texas.

2015 - 2016 / CHICAGO

PIVOTDESIGN

Graphic designer and front-end web developer, worked on a large variety of materials from digital to print, learned how to work in an agency setting, partook in managing various client relations.

2014 - 2015 / CHICAGO

WHAT2DESIGN

Junior graphic designer and front-end web dev, worked with JS, PHP, CSS and wordpress for highly custom builds. Worked on print projects such as; packaging, layout, stationary, posters and branding.

2013 - 2014 / CHICAGO

ACHIEVEMENTS

TUTORING & TEACHING

Tutored the Adobe suite, as well as CSS & HTML to students. Lead skill training and building workshops. Helped develop student work and personal branding. Trained all of my web clients to use a CMS and other progressive tools. 2011 - 2017

DEANS LIST

Named the Dean's list multiple times for GPA. 2010 - 2014

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATION

AIGA / Students In Design managed creative workshops for skill sharing and training. Contributed to the group, set up for the next generation of Students In Design. Organized events, planned meetings, worked closely with the president, helped with web.

2010 - 2014

SKILLS

DESIGN TOOLS
WEB DEVELOPMENT
AUDIO DESIGN
ILLUSTRATION

Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Sketch, Invision CSS3, SVG, HTML5, Sass, JQuery, WordPress, Craft Reason, Ableton, Waves, Garageband, ProTools, LogicPro Hand-typography, Vector Graphics, Sketching, Rendering

CLIENTS

TAZO TEA

Worked closely with a small team and built the Tazo Tea website. I was responsible for all SVG animations as well

as CSS & JQuery animated assets.

BAXALTA

Co-worked on the branding and website design

for this health care giant.

OTHER STUDIO

Had hands on a variety of projects from branding to

advertising art and direction.

CONNECT







